<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Diet Rx Pill</title>
 <link href="https://www.dietrxpill.info/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="https://www.dietrxpill.info"/>
 <updated>2018-02-02T00:38:45-05:00</updated>
 <id>https://www.dietrxpill.info</id>
 <author>
   <name></name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Slimaluma Supplement Pills for Body Fat Loss</title>
   <link href="https://www.dietrxpill.info/slimaluma.html"/>
   <updated>2014-11-07T16:39:15-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.dietrxpill.info/slimaluma</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial;&quot;&gt;Slimaluma is a proprietary standardized extract of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webmd.com/vitamins-supplements/ingredientmono-1160-caralluma.aspx?activeingredientid=1160&amp;amp;activeingredientname=caralluma&quot;&gt;Caralluma Fimbriata&lt;/a&gt;, an edible plant used for centuries in India as a famine food and appetite suppressant. Gencor Pacific has developed a unique patented process to extract the essential constituents of the whole herb without chemical alteration to any of the key constituents, ensuring that the full benefits of the herb are delivered in concentrated form.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;caralluma-extract-supplement-500-mg-per-capsule&quot;&gt;Caralluma extract supplement 500 mg per capsule&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source Naturals Slenderluma uses a trademarked the caralluma extract Slimaluma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/slenderluma.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-39&quot; src=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/slenderluma-300x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;slenderluma&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/slenderluma-300x300.jpg 300w, http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/slenderluma-150x150.jpg 150w, http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/slenderluma-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/slenderluma.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slimaluma is fully managed by Gencor Pacific, Inc., from cultivation of Caralluma Fimbriata to distribution of the extract internationally, ensuring a consistent quality and supply. Caralluma is cultivated on Gencor Pacific farms in India under organic conditions in a dedicated manner, making it sustainable, rather than destroying the ecology or wild harvesting endangered species. The Slimaluma extract is manufactured in a state-of-the-art facility in Bangalore, South India.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Phentermine Diet Pill Side Effects and Benefits &amp;#8211; Does This Prescription Diet Pill Work for Weight Loss? What Safety Issues Should You Be Concerned About?</title>
   <link href="https://www.dietrxpill.info/phenterminedietpill.html"/>
   <updated>2014-11-07T16:32:29-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.dietrxpill.info/phenterminedietpill</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;phentermine-diet-pill-side-effects-and-benefits--does-this-prescription-diet-pill-work-for-weight-loss-what-safety-issues-should-you-be-concerned-about&quot;&gt;Phentermine Diet Pill Side Effects and Benefits – Does This Prescription Diet Pill Work for Weight Loss? What Safety Issues Should You Be Concerned About?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phentermine is a diet pill prescribed by doctors as an appetite suppressant to help reduce weight in overweight patients. Most doctors prescribe phentermine for short-term use. Phentermine is an appetite suppressant of the amphetamine and phenethylamine class. Beta-phenethylamine pharmacological derivative agents include fenfluramine, dexfenfluramine, phentermine and sibutramine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to learn about a natural diet pill with hardly any side effects, consider &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/&quot;&gt;Diet Rx&lt;/a&gt;, a doctor formulated herbal product which does not have phentermine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;phentermine-diet-pill-dosage&quot;&gt;Phentermine Diet Pill Dosage&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phentermine should not be used longer than 8 to12 weeks. Some patients prescribed phentermine diet pill develop drug tolerance, whereby phentermine does not work as well as it did the first few weeks as an appetite suppressant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;phentermine-diet-pill-side-effect&quot;&gt;Phentermine Diet Pill Side Effect&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insomnia are dry mouth are common phentermine side effects. Rapid heart beat is another common high dose phentermine diet pill side effect. Diet Rx natural diet pill does not have these side effects. Some researchers think phentermine causes valvular heart disease with prolonged use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;phentermine-diet-pill-for-weight-loss&quot;&gt;Phentermine Diet Pill for Weight Loss&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Effects on weight reduction and safety of short-term phentermine administration in Korean obese people.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yonsei Med J. 2006. Department of Family Medicine, Yonsei University College of Medicine, Seodaemun-gu, Seoul, Korea.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phentermine diet pill, an appetite suppressant, has been widely used in Korea since 2004. The aim of this study doen at Yonsei University College of Medicine in Seoul, Korea was to determine the effect of phentermine diet pill on weight reduction. Obese subjects received phentermine HCl 37.5 mg or placebo once daily with behavioral therapy for obesity. Mean decrease of both body weight and waist circumference in phentermine diet pill treated subjects were significantly greater than that of placebo group. Significant number of subjects in phentermine diet pill group accomplished weight reduction of 5% or greater from the baseline and 10% or more. There were no significant differences in systolic and diastolic blood pressure between the groups. Dry mouth and insomnia were the only statistically significant adverse events that occurred more frequently in phentermine diet pill group. Most side effects of phentermine were mild to moderate in intensity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q: Until recently I was prescribed Phentermine diet pill as an appetite suppressant, but my doctor said it was time to stop taking it because it is only for temporary use. Phentermine has worked very well to curb my appetite so that I am not hungry all the time and when I am I eat far less than I previously did. I have lost about thirty pounds since May or June, but I’d like to lose 30 more pounds to get to my ideal weight according to the doctor’s chart (about 165-170 lbs). Are there any herbal alternatives for appetite suppression? I have tried Hoodia before, but it required me to take two tablets three times a day. That schedule just does not work for me, so Hoodia did not work for me. I question whether some things that seem so popular are truly what the media hype makes them out to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A: In our opinion, a combination product I have formulated, called Diet Rx, works quite well as an appetite suppressant.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Phaseolus Vulgaris Extract and Weight Loss Information &amp;#8211; Review of Study Results</title>
   <link href="https://www.dietrxpill.info/phaseolusvulgarisextract.html"/>
   <updated>2014-11-07T16:25:29-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.dietrxpill.info/phaseolusvulgarisextract</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;phaseolus-vulgaris-extract-and-weight-loss-information--review-of-study-results&quot;&gt;Phaseolus Vulgaris Extract and Weight Loss Information – Review of Study Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phaseolus vulgaris extract seems to have some benefit as a natural &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/&quot;&gt;diet pill&lt;/a&gt; but not all studies have shown weight loss benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blocking carbohydrate absorption and weight loss: a clinical trial using a proprietary fractionated white &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.raysahelian.com/bean.html&quot;&gt;bean&lt;/a&gt; extract.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Altern Ther Health Med. 2007; Udani J, Singh BB. University of California, Los Angeles School of Medicine, USA.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A proprietary fractionated white bean extract of Phaseolus vulgaris has been shown in vitro to inhibit the digestive enzyme alpha-amylase. This may prevent or delay the digestion of complex carbohydrates, potentially resulting in weight loss. A 4-week randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled study of 25 healthy subjects consuming 1000 mg of a proprietary fractioned Phaseolus vulgaris extract or an identical placebo twice a day before meals in conjunction with a multi-component weight-loss program, including diet, exercise, and behavioral intervention, was conducted. Both groups reduced their weight and waist size significantly from baseline. The active group lost 6.0 lbs and 2.2 in, and the placebo group lost 4.7 lbs and 2.1. The differences between groups were not significant. Through subsequent exploratory analysis to investigate group findings further, subjects were stratified by total dietary carbohydrate intake. This probative analysis revealed that the tertile of subjects who had consumed the most carbohydrates demonstrated significant reductions in both weight and waist size compared with placebo subjects in the same tertile of carbohydrate intake. Subjects who adhere to a program including dietary modification, exercise, and behavioral intervention can significantly reduce their weight and waist size in a short period of time. In an exploratory analysis of data, the tertile of subjects who ate the most carbohydrates experienced a significant reduction in both weight and waist size with the addition of the Phaseolus vulgaris extract compared to the placebo group of the same tertile of carbohydrate consumption. Longer studies with a larger pool of subjects are required to validate these findings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Dietary supplement containing standardized Phaseolus vulgaris extract influences body composition of overweight men and women.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Int J Med Sci. 2007; Celleno L, Tolaini MV, D’Amore A, Perricone NV, Preuss HG. Cosmetic Research Center, dell’Università Cattolica di Roma, Rome, Italy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So-called “starch blockers” are listed among natural weight loss supplements. Theoretically, they may promote weight loss by interfering with the breakdown of complex carbohydrates thereby reducing, or at least slowing, the digestive availability of carbohydrate-derived calories and/or by providing resistant starches to the lower gastrointestinal tract. The present research study examines a dietary supplement containing 445 mg of Phaseolus vulgaris extract derived from the white kidney bean, previously shown to inhibit the activity of the digestive enzyme alpha amylase, on body composition of overweight human subjects. A randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled study was conducted on 60 pre-selected, slightly overweight volunteers, whose weight had been essentially stable for at least six months. The volunteers were divided into two groups, homogeneous for age, gender, and body weight. The test product containing Phaseolus vulgaris extract and the placebo were taken one tablet per day for 30 consecutive days before a main meal rich in carbohydrates. Each subject’s body weight, fat and non-fat mass, skin fold thickness, and waist/hip/thigh circumferences were measured. After 30 days, subjects receiving Phaseolus vulgaris extract with a carbohydrate-rich, 2000- to 2200-calorie diet had significantly greater reduction of body weight, BMI, fat mass, adipose tissue thickness, and waist,/hip/ thigh circumferences while maintaining lean body mass compared to subjects receiving placebo. The results indicate that Phaseolus vulgaris extract produces significant decrements in body weight and suggest decrements in fat mass in the face of maintained lean body mass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Osteoprotective effect of Phaseolus vulgaris L in ovariectomy-induced osteopenia in rats.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Menopause. 2009. Shirke SS, Jadhav SR, Jagtap AG. From the Bombay College of Pharmacy, Kalina, Santacruz, Mumbai, India.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phytoestrogens and phytoestrogen-containing plants are currently being explored as potential candidates for the treatment of estrogen-related disorders. The aim of this study was to evaluate the anti-osteoporotic effect of the phytoestrogen-rich plant Phaseolus vulgaris L, commonly known as French beans. Adult Sprague-Dawley rats were either bilaterally ovariectomized (OVX) or sham operated. OVX and sham control groups were administered vehicle, whereas the other two OVX groups were given 0.15 mg/kg estradiol and 1 g/kg methanolic extract of Phaseolus vulgaris seeds orally for 10 weeks (10 rats per group). At autopsy, blood, urine, bones, and uteri of the animals were collected. Serum was evaluated for estradiol, calcium (Ca), phosphorus, alkaline phosphatase, tartarate resistant acid phosphatase, and urine for Ca. The bone density, ash density, mineral content, and mechanical strength of bones was evaluated. Treatment with extract of Phaseolus vulgaris seeds prevented estrogen deficiency-induced osteopenia without affecting the uterine mass. The promising results of the study warrant further investigation of extract of Phaseolus vulgaris seeds as a potential candidate for the treatment of postmenopausal osteoporosis.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Guarana Side Effects, Benefits and the Risk and Danger of Overdosing</title>
   <link href="https://www.dietrxpill.info/guaranasideeffects.html"/>
   <updated>2014-11-07T16:18:04-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.dietrxpill.info/guaranasideeffects</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;guarana-side-effects-benefits-and-the-risk-and-danger-of-overdosing&quot;&gt;Guarana Side Effects, Benefits and the Risk and Danger of Overdosing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guarana is also known as Paullinia cupana, Brazilian cocoa, guarana bread, and guarana paste or gum. Guarana is found in some soft drinks imported from South America in a manner similar to American soft-drinks fortified with caffeine. Some over the counter weight loss pills contain guarana. Guarana side effects can occur when ingesting a high amount, including irritability and rapid heart beat. Guarana use can improve alertness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to eat less by taking a product without guarana, consider &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/&quot;&gt;Diet Rx pill&lt;/a&gt;, formulated by a medical doctor. Diet Rx reduces appetite without side effects. Contains &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acetyllcarnitine.info/&quot;&gt;acety l carnitine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;guarana-and-caffeine&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.preworkoutbuzz.com/creatine-and-caffeine-for-strength-and-energy/&quot;&gt;Guarana and Caffeine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guarana contains caffeine and has been used as a stimulant and appetite suppressant. Guarana also has small amounts of theophylline and theobromine, along with tannins such as proanthocyanidins. Tannins are bitter-tasting plant polyphenols that bind and precipitate proteins. Condensed tannins are also known as proanthocyanidins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;guarana-side-effects&quot;&gt;Guarana Side Effects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guarana side effects include loss of appetite, nervousness, irritability, anxiety, insomnia, stomach upset, and headache. A serious high dose guarana side effect is abnormal heart rhythm, particularly if guarana is combined with phentermine, alcohol, or other drugs and substances that influence heart rhythm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We suggest not using guarana long term unless you take a 2 day break each week and a full week off each month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;guarana-in-energy-drinks-and-potential-side-effects&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.livescience.com/36119-truth-guarana.html&quot;&gt;Guarana in Energy Drinks&lt;/a&gt; and Potential Side Effects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New-onset seizures in adults: possible association with consumption of popular energy drinks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epilepsy Behav. 2007. Iyadurai SJ, Chung SS. Department of Neurology, Barrow Neurological Institute, St. Joseph’s Hospital and Medical Center, Phoenix, AZ, USA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Energy drinks contain a mixture of compounds, of which caffeine, guarana, and herbal supplements such as ginkgo and ginseng are major components. Survey of popular literature reveals anecdotal observations of adverse events associated with consumption of energy drinks. However, there are no reported cases in the published literature. We report a series of four patients who had discrete seizures on multiple occasions, following heavy consumption of energy drinks. Once the patients were abstinent from the energy drinks, no recurrent seizures were reported. We propose that the large consumption of energy drinks rich in caffeine, taurine, and guarana seed extract could have provoked these seizures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;guarana-effects-on-humans--mood-and-alertness&quot;&gt;Guarana Effects on Humans – Mood and Alertness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A double-blind, placebo-controlled, multi-dose evaluation of the acute behavioural effects of guaraná in humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;J Psychopharmacol. 2007. Haskell CF, Kennedy DO, Wesnes KA, Milne AL, Scholey AB. Human Cognitive Neuroscience Unit, Division of Psychology, Northumbria University, Newcastle upon Tyne, UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers at Northumbria University, Newcastle upon Tyne, UK tested for side effects of guaraná plant in humans. This double-blind, counterbalanced, placebo-controlled guarana study evaluated the acute mood and cognitive effects throughout the day of four different doses (37.5 mg, 75 mg, 150 mg and 300 mg) of a standardised guaraná extract (PC-102). Guaraná improved secondary memory performance and increased alert and content mood ratings. The two lower doses produced more positive cognitive effects than the higher doses. This research supports previous findings of cognitive improvements following 75 mg guaraná and provides the first exploration of different dose effects of guaraná in humans. The findings suggest that the guarana effects cannot be attributed to caffeine alone. No major guarana side effects were reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;improved-cognitive-performance-in-human-volunteers-following-administration-of-guarana-paullinia-cupana-extract-comparison-and-interaction-with-panax-ginseng&quot;&gt;Improved Cognitive Performance in Human Volunteers Following Administration of Guarana (Paullinia Cupana) Extract: Comparison and Interaction with Panax Ginseng&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pharmacol Biochem Behav. 2004. Kennedy DO, Haskell CF, Wesnes KA, Scholey AB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human Cognitive Neuroscience Unit, Division of Psychology, Northumbria University, Newcastle upon Tyne, NE1 8ST, United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this double-blind, counterbalanced, placebo-controlled study, the cognitive and mood effects of separate single doses of: 75 mg of a dried ethanolic extract of guarana (approx 12% caffeine), 200 mg of Panax ginseng (G115), and their combination (75 mg/200 mg), were assessed in 28 healthy young (18-24) participants. In comparison to placebo, all three treatments resulted in improved task performance throughout the day. In the case of guarana, improvements were seen across ‘attention’ tasks (but with some evidence of reduced accuracy), and on a sentence verification task. While also increasing the speed of attention task performance, both ginseng and the ginseng – guarana combination also enhanced the speed of memory task performance, with little evidence of modulated accuracy. Guarana and the combination, and to a lesser extent ginseng, also led to significant improvements in serial subtraction task performance. Given the low caffeine content (9 mg) of this dose of guarana extract, the effects are unlikely to be attributable to its caffeine content. No significant guarana side effects were reported.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Glucomannan Fiber Benefit and Side Effects, Use for Losing Pounds and Satiety</title>
   <link href="https://www.dietrxpill.info/glucomannansideeffects.html"/>
   <updated>2014-11-07T16:10:17-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.dietrxpill.info/glucomannansideeffects</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;glucomannan-fiber-benefit-and-side-effects-use-for-losing-pounds-and-satiety&quot;&gt;Glucomannan Fiber Benefit and Side Effects, Use for Losing Pounds and Satiety&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glucomannan root is a water soluble dietary fiber that has been used in East Asia for more than a thousand years. This dietary fiber is the main polysaccharide obtained from the tubers of the Amorphophallus konjac plant. The chemical structure consists, mainly, of mannose and glucose. Glucomannan fiber has a extraordinarily high water holding capacity, forming highly viscous solutions when dissolved in water. Glucomannan has the highest molecular weight and viscosity of any known dietary fiber. Glucomannan is effective for weight loss due to the satiety sensation that it produces. Glucomanna is also a remedy for constipation because it increases fecal volume. Glucomannan firber may be considered as a substance to lower cholesterol levels since it interferes in the transport of cholesterol and of bile acids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glucomannan fiber is found in an effective diet pill called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/&quot;&gt;Diet Rx&lt;/a&gt; which helps you eat less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;glucomannan-side-effects&quot;&gt;Glucomannan Side Effects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No major glucomannan side effects have been reported in the medical literature as of 2009 except for case reports as listed below. Due to its ability to absorb water, constipation could occur if little water in ingested. High amounts of glucomannan could lead to gastrointestinal side effects mostly of stomach cramps and intestinal upset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;natures-way-glucomannan&quot;&gt;Nature’s Way Glucomannan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/glucomannan.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-30&quot; src=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/glucomannan-300x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;glucomannan&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/glucomannan-300x300.jpg 300w, http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/glucomannan-150x150.jpg 150w, http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/glucomannan-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/glucomannan.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glucomannan ( Amorphophallus konjac ) is a 100% dietary fiber source obtained from the root of the konjac plant. Glucomannan is an excellent addition to a sensible weight loss program. This glucomannan product is especially grown and prepared to Japan according to exacting specifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glucomannan has the ability to absorb up to 50 times its weight in water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supplement Facts, 3 capsules&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glucomannan (root) – 1.99 grams&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;glucomannan-and-weight-loss&quot;&gt;Glucomannan and Weight Loss&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certain fiber supplements added to a low caloric diet have additional effects on weight reduction in overweight subjects. Glucomannan induces body weight reduction in healthy overweight subjects. Glucomannan supplement does not appear to have any significant side effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;experiences-with-three-different-fiber-supplements-in-weight-reduction&quot;&gt;Experiences with Three Different Fiber Supplements in Weight Reduction.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Med Sci Monit. 2005. Birketvedt GS, Shimshi M, Erling T. Laboratory of Gastroenterology, Institute of Clinical Medicine, University of Tromsø, Tromsø, Norway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers at Institute of Clinical Medicine, University of Tromsø, Tromsø, Norway comparde the effect of various commercial fiber supplements (glucomannan, guar gum and alginate) on weight reduction in healthy overweight subjects. One hundred and seventy six men and women were included to receive either active fiber substance or placebo in randomized placebo-controlled studies. The fiber supplements consisted of the viscous fibers glucomannan (Chrombalance), glucomannan and guar gum (Appe-Trim) and glucomannan, guar gum and alginat (Glucosahl). All fiber supplements plus a balanced 1200 kcal diet induced significantly weight reduction more than placebo and diet alone, during a five week observation period. However, there were no significant differences between the different fibers in their ability to induce weight reduction. Glucomannan induced body weight reduction in healthy overweight subjects, whereas the addition of guar gum and alginate did not seem to cause additional loss of weight. No significant glucomannan side effects were reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;effect-on-cholesterol&quot;&gt;Effect on Cholesterol&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The use of glucomannan can reduce serum cholesterol levels. Glucomannan and a combination of glucomannan and plant sterols substantially decreases plasma LDL cholesterol concentrations. Glucomannan may even be used in children who have high cholesterol levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;konjac-glucomannan-and-constipation&quot;&gt;Konjac Glucomannan and Constipation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Konjac glucomannan relieves constipation since it increases stool bulk and improves colonic ecology. Konjac glucomannan supplement use promotes colonic fermentation, indicated by a decrease in fecal pH and increased fecal short-chain fatty acid concentrations. Supplementation of Konjac glucomannan to a low-fiber diet enhances defecation frequency, possibly by increasing the stool bulk, thus promoting the growth of lactic acid bacteria and colonic fermentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glucomannan is beneficial in chlidren in the treatment of constipation with and without encopresis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;glucomannan-beneficial-for-the-colon&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/dr-mark-hyman/fiber-health-the-super-fi_b_594153.html&quot;&gt;Glucomannan Beneficial for the Colon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Konjac acts as a natural laxative by increasing stool bulk and improving colonic ecology in healthy adults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nutrition. 2006. Institute of Nutritional Science, Chung Shan Medical University, Taichung, Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;researchers from the Institute of Nutritional Science, Chung Shan Medical University, in Taiwan, conducted a placebo-controlled study with volunteers who consumed Konjac glucomannan progressively, and a 21-d Konjac glucomannan supplemented period (1.5 g/meal, 4.5 g/d). Eight healthy adults consumed 7-d cycle menus of typical low-fiber Chinese food throughout the study. The Konjac glucomannan supplement significantly increased the mean defecation frequency (number/day), wet stool weight, and dry stool weight. Konjac glucomannan significantly promoted the fecal concentrations of lactobacilli and total bacteria, and promoted the daily output of bifidobacteria, lactobacilli, and total bacteria. Konjac glucomannan supplement also promoted colonic fermentation. Supplementation of Konjac glucomannan into a low-fiber diet promoted the defecation frequency in healthy adults, by increasing the stool bulk, thus promoting the growth of lactic acid bacteria and colonic fermentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;glucomannan-beneficial-for-cholesterol-and-blood-lipids&quot;&gt;Glucomannan Beneficial for Cholesterol and Blood Lipids&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Effect of plant sterols and glucomannan on lipids in individuals with and without type II diabetes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eur J Clin Nutr. 2006. School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition, McGill University, Montreal, Québec, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this study was to determine whether supplements of plant sterols and/or glucomannan improve lipid profile and cholesterol biosynthesis in mildly type II diabetic and non-diabetic subjects with elevated cholesterol levesl. Subjects were supplemented with plant sterols (1.8 g/day), glucomannan (10 grams a day), a combination of glucomannan and plant sterols, and a placebo, provided in the form of bars.Overall plasma cholesterol concentrations were lowered after combination treatment compared to control. Plasma low-density lipoprotein (LDL) cholesterol concentrations were decreased after glucomannan and combination treatments compared to control. The results of lipid profiles did not differ between subject groups. The results suggest that glucomannan and a combination of glucomannan and plant sterols substantially improves plasma LDL cholesterol concentrations. No significant glucomannan side effects were reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glucomannan comes from the Amorphophallus konjac plant but there are other sources, for instance glucomannan from Dioscorea esculenta tubers. Chemical analysis reveals that Aloe vera contains various carbohydrate polymers, notably glucomannans, along with a range of other organic and inorganic components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;glucomannan-side-effects-of-hepatitis&quot;&gt;Glucomannan Side Effects of Hepatitis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Acute hepatitis of cholestatic type possibly associated with the use of glucomannan (amorphophalus konjac).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;J Hepatol. 2004. Villaverde AF, Benlloch S, Berenguer M, Miguel Rayón J, Pina R, Berenguer J.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;glucomannan-and-ghrelin&quot;&gt;Glucomannan and Ghrelin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediate and long-term effects of glucomannan on total ghrelin and leptin in type 2 diabetes mellitus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diabetes Res Clin Pract. 2009.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Effects of glucomannan as a supplementary treatment in type 2 diabetes mellitus were investigated by measuring ghrelin, leptin and insulin responses to OGTT. Glucomannan enhanced prandial ghrelin reduction when given before glucose load and impeded the rise of fasting ghrelin after 4-week supplement. Ghrelin-induced feeding may be attenuated by glucomannan.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Cordia Salicfolia Herb &amp;#8211; Does This Plant Supplement Lead to Weight Loss?</title>
   <link href="https://www.dietrxpill.info/cordiasalicifolia.html"/>
   <updated>2014-11-07T15:57:29-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.dietrxpill.info/cordiasalicifolia</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;cordia-salicfolia-herb--does-this-plant-supplement-lead-to-weight-loss-what-do-the-research-studies-indicate&quot;&gt;Cordia Salicfolia Herb – Does This Plant Supplement Lead to Weight Loss? What Do the Research Studies Indicate?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cordia salicifolia is the botanical name for Cha de Bugre, a plant used in Brazil for appetite suppression and weight loss that is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.preworkoutbuzz.com/garcinia-cambogia/&quot;&gt;similar to Garcinia Cambrogia&lt;/a&gt;. Little human research is available regarding its benefits as a supplement. There are other herbs and supplements that are promoted for weight loss or appetite suppression as listed below. It would be interesting to see future research regarding Cordia salicifolia in humans to determine whether it is effective for weight loss and whether it has any side effects of concern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For an effective natural appetite suppressing product, see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/&quot;&gt;Diet Rx&lt;/a&gt;. Just about everyone who has used this product has noticed appetite suppression without any untoward side effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cordia-salicifolia-plant&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rain-tree.com/chadebugre.htm#.VIh0BclUcpE&quot;&gt;Cordia Salicifolia Plant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cordia salicifolia grows in Brazil, Argentina and Paraguay. Also known as Porangaba, Cordia salicifolia is a small tree that normally grows to a height of 20 to 40 feet. The tree produces a small red fruit that resembles a coffee bean that can be roasted to make a coffee substitute. Cordia salicifolia apparently has caffeine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cordia-salicifolia-supplement-availability&quot;&gt;Cordia Salicifolia Supplement Availability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raw material suppliers cha de bugre powder and cha de bugre extracts. One common cha de bugre extract is a 10 to 1 concentration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;compounds-in-cordia-salicifolia&quot;&gt;Compounds in Cordia Salicifolia&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These include caffeine, allantoin, and allantoic acid. Spathulenol is another substance found in cordia salicifolia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cordia-salicifolia-research-studies&quot;&gt;Cordia Salicifolia Research studies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;antiviral-activity-of-an-extract-of-cordia-salicifolia-on-herpes-simplex-virus-type-1&quot;&gt;Antiviral Activity of an Extract of Cordia Salicifolia on Herpes Simplex Virus Type 1.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planta Med. 1990.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A partially purified extract (COL 1-6) from whole plant of Cordia salicifolia showed an inhibitory effect on herpes simplex virus type 1 (HSV-1). The activity of COL 1-6 on different steps of HSV-1 replication in HeLa cells was investigated. Under single-cycle replication conditions, COL 1-6 exerted a greater than 99.9% inhibition in virus yield when added to the cells 3 h or 1.5 h before infection, and even when added 8 h after infection the extract still caused a greater than 99% inhibition. The extract has been shown to have a direct virucidal activity. And also, analysis of early events following infection showed that COL 1-6 affected viral penetration in HeLa cells but did not interfere with adsorption to the cells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;emails&quot;&gt;Emails&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q. I read your email about Cordia salicifolia on this website and wanted to let you know that I am also a manager of a vitamin store and received this promotional material: “Cordia salicifolia 10:1 extract is unlike anything else for energy on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A: In Brazil it is called café do mato, or coffee of the woods for it’s powerful stimulant effects. It is brewed in large drums at times of festival in Brazil and the people drink it to sustain their energy thru the night. Cordia salicifolia is a very clean energy, the caffeine levels are surprisingly low.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Chitosan Fat Blocker Benefits and Side Effects &amp;#8211; Do Such Pills Work for Weight Loss?</title>
   <link href="https://www.dietrxpill.info/chitosanfatblocker.html"/>
   <updated>2014-11-07T15:46:07-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.dietrxpill.info/chitosanfatblocker</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;chitosan-fat-blocker-benefits-and-side-effects--do-such-pills-work-for-weight-loss&quot;&gt;Chitosan Fat Blocker Benefits and Side Effects – &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mayoclinic.org/healthy-living/weight-loss/in-depth/weight-loss/art-20046409&quot;&gt;Do Such Pills Work for Weight Loss&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chitosan is a dietary supplement promoted as a common fat blocker similar to garcinia cambogia. Chitosan is made from chitin, found in the skeleton of shrimp, crab, and other shellfish. Chitosan cannot be digested; therefore it passes through the intestinal tract unabsorbed without adding any calories. The chemical nature makes it bind with fatty foods, removing some of the fat from the intestinal tract rather than allowing it to be absorbed. The results of studies with chitosan fat blocker have been mixed. Some studies showed chitosan dietary supplement to be helpful, while others did not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to eat less, consider &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info&quot;&gt;Diet Rx&lt;/a&gt;, a medical doctor formulated all natural appetite suppressant composed of 22 natural herbs and nutrients. Diet Rx does not have chitosan fat blocker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;source-naturals--diet-chitosan-500-mg-240-caps&quot;&gt;Source Naturals – Diet Chitosan, 500 mg, 240 Caps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/Source-Naturals-Diet-Chitosan-021078010241.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-medium wp-image-25&quot; src=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/Source-Naturals-Diet-Chitosan-021078010241-161x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Source-Naturals-Diet-Chitosan&quot; width=&quot;161&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/Source-Naturals-Diet-Chitosan-021078010241-161x300.jpg 161w, http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/Source-Naturals-Diet-Chitosan-021078010241.jpg 538w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 161px) 100vw, 161px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chitosan, a fiber derived from chitin in shell-fish, is a nondigestible aminopolysaccharide. Chitosan is synthesized by removing acetyl groups from chitin, through a process called deacetylation. This process enhances the activity by improving its solubility in the acidic environment of the stomach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supplement Facts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chitosan (minimum 90% deacetylated chitin) 1 gram&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggested Use: Two chitosan capsules before lunch and two capsules before dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chitosan-fat-blocker-for-weight-loss&quot;&gt;Chitosan Fat Blocker for Weight Loss&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evaluating efficacy of a chitosan product using a double-blinded, placebo-controlled protocol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;J Am Coll Nutr. 2006. Kaats GR, Michalek JE, Preuss HG. Health and Medical Research Center, San Antonio, TX, USA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These researchers at Health and Medical Research Center in San Antonio, Texas, looked into the effectiveness of a chitosan fat blocker dietary supplement on body composition. In a randomized, double-blinded, placebo-controlled dietary intervention protocol, subjects were assigned to a chitosan fat blocker treatment group, a placebo group (P) and a control group (C). The chitosan fat blocker treatment group took six 500 mg chitosan capsules per day and both chitosan fat blocker treatment group and P groups wore pedometers during their waking hours and recorded daily step totals. The C group followed weight loss programs of their choice, and took the same baseline and ending tests. Compared to C, the chitosan fat blocker treatment group lost more weight (-2.8 lbs vs. +0.8 lbs) and fat mass (-2.6 lbs vs. +0.1 lbs). Compared to P, the chitosan fat blocker treatment group lost more weight (-2.8 lbs. vs. -0.6 lbs), % fat (-0.8% vs. +0.4%, fat mass and had a greater body composition improvement index. These data provide evidence for the efficacy of a chitosan fat blocker compound to facilitate the depletion of excess body fat under free-living conditions with minimal loss of fat-free or lean body mass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chitosan: antimicrobial activity and potential applications for preserving minimally processed strawberries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food Microbiol. 2008. Campaniello D, Bevilacqua A, Sinigaglia M, Corbo MR. Campaniello D, Sinigaglia M, Corbo MR. Department of Food Science, Faculty of Agricultural, Foggia University Foggia, Italy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this research the possible use of chitosan coating on fresh-cut strawberries was investigated. Manually sliced strawberries were treated with a solution of 1% chitosan, packaged in modified atmosphere with high (80%) and low (5%) percentage of oxygen and then stored at 4, 8, 12 and 15 degrees C. A chitosan coating inhibited the growth of microorganisms and affected significantly and positively the stability time of the products, above all when the samples were packaged in modified atmosphere (with low and high percentage of oxygen). Besides, the presence of high percentage of oxygen, combined with chitosan coating, seemed to affect positively the colour. The data revealed that applying a chitosan coating prolonged effectively the quality and extended the shelf life of fresh-cut strawberries.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Cascara Sagrada Herb &amp;#8211; Does This Herbal Root Product Use Lead to Achieve Weight Loss?</title>
   <link href="https://www.dietrxpill.info/cascarasagradaherb.html"/>
   <updated>2014-11-07T15:38:08-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.dietrxpill.info/cascarasagradaherb</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;cascara-sagrada-herb--does-this-herbal-root-product-use-lead-to-achieve-weight-loss&quot;&gt;Cascara Sagrada Herb – Does This Herbal Root Product Use Lead to Achieve Weight Loss?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dried cascara sagrada bark is used as a laxative. The cascara sagrada tree is cultivated in North America and Kenya. The cascara sagrada bark is aged for a year so that the active principles become milder, as freshly dried bark produces too strong a laxative for safe use. Cascara sagrada herb also contains a compound that induces vomiting. Cascara consists of the dried bark of Rhamnus Purshiana (Fam. Rhamnaceae), a small tree of Northern California.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cascara-sagrada-herb-and-weight-loss&quot;&gt;Cascara Sagrada Herb and Weight Loss&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cascara sagrada herb is a common ingredient used in weight loss products. One of the few herbs approved as an over-the-counter drug by the FDA, it is a strong stimulant laxative. We don’t think a laxative is a good way to lose weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/&quot;&gt;Diet Rx&lt;/a&gt;, a highly popular doctor formulated natural obesity pill product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;availability&quot;&gt;Availability&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cascara sagrada herb is available in capsules, extracts, and as dried bark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;natures-way-cascara-sagrada-herb&quot;&gt;Nature’s Way Cascara Sagrada Herb&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/NWY-11308-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft wp-image-21 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/NWY-11308-2-300x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;NWY-11308-2&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/NWY-11308-2-300x300.jpg 300w, http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/NWY-11308-2-150x150.jpg 150w, http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/NWY-11308-2-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/NWY-11308-2.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indications:&lt;/strong&gt; For relief of occasional constipation (irregularity). Cascara sagrada herb in many cases produces a bowel movement in 6 to 12 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Directions:&lt;/strong&gt; Adults and children 12 years of age and over. Take 1 or 2 cascara sagrada herb capsules once a day at bedtime with a full glass of water. Children 2 to under 12 years of age. Take 1 cascara sagrada capsule once a day at bedtime with a full glass of water. Children under 2 years of age: Consult a doctor. To avoid cascara sagrada herb side effects, do not use longer than one week without taking a break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Active ingredient:&lt;/strong&gt; 425 mg Cascara Sagrada herb bark (Rhamnus purshiana)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;short-term-side-effects&quot;&gt;Short Term Side Effects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cascara sagrada herb does not have significant side effects as long as it is not used for more than a week or two at a time without a break. It is best to avoid cascara sagrada herb if you have a chronic intestinal condition such as ulcerative colitis, or diverticular disease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;long-term-cascara-sagrada-herb-side-effects&quot;&gt;Long Term Cascara Sagrada Herb Side Effects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When cascara sagrada herb or other anthraquinone containing plants are used for prolonged periods, potentially serious side effects can occur. These cascara sagrada side effects may include cramping in the abdomen and loss of body fluids. Dark pigmentation in the colon can occur and this is called melanosis coli.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Misuse of this cascara sagrada herb has caused problems with the body’s minerals (such as potassium, sodium). This herb should not be taken if you are pregnant or breastfeeding. Cascara sagrada herb may interact with medications such as Lanoxin and diuretics (water pills, used to treat hypertension and other health problems).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Calcium Pyruvate Side Effects, Benefits and Food Intake Reduction</title>
   <link href="https://www.dietrxpill.info/calciumpyruvatesideeffects.html"/>
   <updated>2014-11-07T15:25:47-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.dietrxpill.info/calciumpyruvatesideeffects</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;calcium-pyruvate-side-effects-and-benefits--is-this-product-beneficial-for-food-intake-reduction&quot;&gt;Calcium Pyruvate Side Effects and Benefits – Is This Product Beneficial for Food Intake Reduction?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calcium pyruvate is formed in the body during digestion of carbohydrates and protein from food. Found in the form of pyruvic acid, pyruvate can be found in various foods including red apples, cheese and red wine. Claims that calcium pyruvate improves metabolism, decreases appetite and aids in weight loss need further study. We have not come across any new human studies with calcium pyruvate supplementation in the years 2007 to 2009.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider Diet Rx, a highly effective doctor formulated natural obesity pill produc without phentermine, drugs, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.raysahelian.com/hormone.html&quot;&gt;hormones&lt;/a&gt;, or stimulants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;calcium-pyruvate-side-effects&quot;&gt;Calcium Pyruvate Side Effects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calcium pyruvate appears to be relatively safe and no major side effects have been reported in the medical literature as of November 2007.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;calcium-pyruvate-and-exercise-training&quot;&gt;Calcium Pyruvate and Exercise Training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Effects of calcium pyruvate supplementation during training on body composition, exercise capacity, and metabolic responses to exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nutrition. 2005. Koh-Banerjee PK, Ferreira MP, Greenwood M, Bowden RG, Cowan PN, Almada AL, Kreider RB. Department of Preventive Medicine, University of Tennessee Medical School, Memphis, Tennessee, USA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We evaluated the effects of calcium pyruvate supplementation during training on body composition and metabolic responses to exercise. Twenty-three untrained females took either 5 g of calcium pyruvate or a placebo (PL) twice daily for 30 d while participating in a supervised exercise program. No significant differences were observed between groups in energy intake or training volume. Results indicate that calcium pyruvate supplementation during training does not significantly affect body composition or exercise performance and may negatively affect some blood lipid levels. No significant calcium pyruvate side effects were reported.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;calcium-pyruvate-supplement-questions&quot;&gt;Calcium Pyruvate Supplement Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q. Can taking 2000 mg a day of the calcium pyruvate extra strength cause any mood swings that you know of?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A. We have not had this reported to us yet.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Caffeine pill &amp;#8211; Can it Help You Lose Weight?  Side effects, Safety Issues and Heart Disease</title>
   <link href="https://www.dietrxpill.info/caffeinepill.html"/>
   <updated>2014-11-07T14:57:56-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.dietrxpill.info/caffeinepill</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;caffeine-pill--can-it-help-you-lose-weight-what-are-the-side-effects-safety-issues-and-potential-danger-for-those-with-heart-disease&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mayoclinic.org/healthy-living/weight-loss/expert-answers/caffeine/faq-20058459&quot;&gt;Caffeine pill – Can it help you lose weight?&lt;/a&gt; What are the side effects, safety issues and potential danger for those with heart disease?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial;&quot;&gt;Caffeine is a xanthine alkaloid compound that acts as a psychoactive stimulant in humans. As if drinking coffee was not enough to ingest your daily caffeine need, caffeine in pill form is sold by a number of companies. Caffeine pills are sometimes advertised as being “as safe as coffee” but unlike coffee one can easy overdose on caffeine by taking too many caffeine pills. Those who take too many caffeine pills are likely to have side effects and feel anxiety, restlessness, sweating, rapid heart beat, and other unpleasant feeling.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people take caffeine pills for mental alertness and energy not realizing there are much better and healthier alternatives. For mental alertness, improved focus and better mood, consider Mind Power Rx.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others take caffeine pills as a diet aid not realizing that more effective products are available. If you would like to eat less with the help of a natural, safe diet pill, consider &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/&quot;&gt;Diet Rx pill&lt;/a&gt;, formulated by a medical doctor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;source&quot;&gt;Source&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caffeine is probably the most frequently ingested pharmacologically active substance in the world. It is found in common beverages (coffee, tea, soft drinks), in products containing cocoa or chocolate, and in medications. Caffeine is found in varying quantities in the beans, leaves, and fruit of many plants, where it acts as a natural pesticide that paralyzes and kills certain insects feeding on the plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;caffeine-for-humans&quot;&gt;Caffeine for Humans&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caffeine is most commonly consumed by humans in infusions extracted from the beans of the coffee plant and the leaves of the tea bush, as well as from various foods and drinks containing products derived from the kola nut or from cacao. Other sources include yerba mate and guarana berries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;caffeine-pill-side-effects&quot;&gt;Caffeine Pill Side Effects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caffeine, the natural substance found in many foods and beverages including coffee, tea and chocolate, can cause symptoms that can vary widely from person to person. Excessive use of caffeine pills can have side effects, including those serious enough that can lead to emergency room visits. Some people, without realizing, may drink excessive amounts of coffee or tea, then use medications with caffeine, or ingest caffeine in the form a caffeine-enhanced beverage. Some may even take a caffeine pill dietary supplement. People using caffeine pills and supplements need to know that caffeine is a drug and it’s overuse is potentially harmful, especially when it is mixed with other medications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caffeine pill side effects include insomnia, palpitations, tremors, sweating, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea, chest paints, and neurological symptoms. Caffeine pills are easily available, so some people may not consider them to be very dangerous. Like any medication, though, an overdose is potentially fatal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial;&quot;&gt;If you are sensitive, you may get the following symptoms and caffeine side effects even with drinking one cup: Rapid or increased heart rate; Frequent urination; Nausea and vomiting; Restlessness and insomnial  Anxiety and depression; Shakiness or tremors. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;caffeine-pill-in-combination-with-other-supplements-for-weight-loss&quot;&gt;Caffeine Pill in Combination with Other Supplements for Weight Loss&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use of caffeine in combination with other supplements could lead to a modest weight loss. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.serenity-station.com/caffeine-and-l-theanine/&quot;&gt;Caffeine is often combined with theanine&lt;/a&gt; due to their synergistic properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Body fat loss achieved by stimulation of thermogenesis by a combination of bioactive food ingredients: a placebo-controlled, double-blind 8-week intervention in obese subjects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Int J Obes 2007. Belza A, Frandsen E, Kondrup J. Department of Human Nutrition, Centre for Advanced Food Studies, The Royal Veterinary and Agricultural University, Frederiksberg C, Denmark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A combination of tyrosine, capsaicin, catechines and caffeine may stimulate the sympathetic nervous system and promote satiety, lipolysis and thermogenesis. In total, 80 overweight-obese subjects underwent an initial 4-week hypocaloric diet. Those who lost &amp;gt;4% body weight were instructed to consume a hypocaloric diet and were randomized to receive either placebo or bioactive supplement in a double-blind, 8-week intervention. The bioactive supplement increased 4-h thermogenesis by 90 kJ more than placebo, and the effect was maintained after 8 weeks and accompanied by a slight reduction in fat mass. These bioactive components may support weight maintenance after a hypocaloric diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;caffeine-pill-products&quot;&gt;Caffeine Pill Products&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are hundreds of caffeine pill products on the market, here is an example of some of these products:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NoDoz caffeine pill – Each caplet contains: Caffeine (200 mg)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay-Awake&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 Ever Fit caffeine pill with 200 mg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natrol High caffeine pill with 200 mg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pep-Back Peak Performance Stimulant caffeine pill caplets with taurine has 200 mg of caffeine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wakeups-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick-Pep&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Revive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alert&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Penguin Mints – caffeine pills as mint candy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pro-plus – UK brand caffeine pill&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vivarin caffeine pills – “Vivarin is used for a safe, fast pick up anytime you feel drowsy and need to be alert. The caffeine in Vivarin is less irritating to your stomach than coffee, according to a government appointed panel of experts. The Active Ingredient in the caffeine pill is 200 mg. of Caffeine.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;caffeine-in-weight-loss-pills&quot;&gt;Caffeine in Weight Loss Pills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Caffeine is commonly found in weight loss pills. Caffeine is also included in headache remedies such as Excedrin. When consumed in pill form, you will often ingest two to four times the amount of caffeine that is in most common beverages. These increased levels of caffeine may be helpful in weight loss but at a price. The side effects of caffeine pills are unpleasant and can be dangerous if misused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;some-nutritional-supplements-have-hidden-caffeine&quot;&gt;Some nutritional supplements have hidden caffeine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;USDA Agricultural Research Service scientists analyzed more than 50 dietary supplements and found about half contained the caffeine equivalent of up to two cups of coffee. But supplements aren’t required to list caffeine on the label unless they contain added pure caffeine. The stimulant occurs naturally not only in tea and coffee, but also in “botanicals” such as guarana, yerba mate, green tea extract and kola nut. Of the 28 analyzed products that voluntarily listed a caffeine amount on the label, 25 were accurate within 20%. Among all 50 pills, caffeine levels ranged from zero to 800 milligrams per dose (more than in eight cups of coffee).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;caffeine-content-in-decaffeinated-coffee&quot;&gt;Caffeine Content in Decaffeinated Coffee&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decaffeinated coffee is not caffeine free. Most often it has about a fifth to a tenth of the amount of caffeine in regular coffee. Decaffeinated coffee from many coffee shops contain caffeine averaging about 1 mg of caffeine per ounce of decaf coffee. In some people who are sensitive to caffeine and drink several cups a day, even moderate caffeine levels can increase heart rate, blood pressure, agitation and anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A regular cup of coffee has from 85 to 100 milligrams of caffeine. In one study, most of the 10- to 12-ounce decafs tested had less than five milligrams of caffeine. The decaffeinating process doesn’t eliminate 100 percent of the caffeine in coffee. On average 16-ounce servings of decaf has a caffeine content ranging from nine to 14 milligrams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;caffeine-pill-study--influence-on-hormone-levels&quot;&gt;Caffeine Pill Study – Influence on Hormone Levels&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Metabolic and hormonal effects of caffeine: randomized, double-blind, placebo-controlled crossover trial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Metabolism. 2007. Mackenzie T, Comi R, Sluss P, Keisari R, Manwar S, Larson R, Baron JA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Department of Medicine, Dartmouth Medical School, Hanover, NH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short-term studies, caffeine has been shown to increase insulin levels, reduce insulin sensitivity, and increase cortisol levels. We evaluated the effect of oral intake of 200 mg of caffeine pill taken twice a day for 7 days on glucose metabolism, as well as on serum cortisol, dehydroepiandrosterone (DHEA), and androstenedione, and on nighttime salivary melatonin. There were no differences in glucose, DHEA, androstenedione, and melatonin between treatment periods. Daily caffeine intake reduces insulin sensitivity; the effect persists for at least a week and is evident up to 12 hours after administration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;emails&quot;&gt;Emails&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Q. I am looking for a caffeine pill alternative. if you had to choose just one or the other of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rhodiola.mobi/&quot;&gt;rhodiola&lt;/a&gt; or maca, is there one that is better suited as an alternative?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A. Most people would choose maca herb, but we have many people who swear by rhodiola herb, also.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Bitter Melon Diabetes Benefit &amp;#8211; Does this herbal extract control blood sugar and help people with diabetes? What is the proper dosage</title>
   <link href="https://www.dietrxpill.info/bittermelondiabetes.html"/>
   <updated>2014-11-07T14:49:01-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.dietrxpill.info/bittermelondiabetes</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial;&quot;&gt;Bitter melon is traditionally used for diabetes in Asia, Africa, and South America. Bitter melon is also a medicinal plant used by Ayurvedic doctors of medicine to benefit various conditions, including diabetes. In the Philippines, bitter melon is widely used and advertised for patients who have diabetes.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitter melon is found in a product called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/&quot;&gt;Diet Rx&lt;/a&gt; which helps users eat less food. When less food is consumed, blood sugar does not rise as much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial;&quot;&gt;Composition of bitter melon and benefit to those with diabetes&lt;br /&gt; Bitter melon or bitter gourd is a vegetable that grows in the tropics. It contains substances with blood sugar managing properties such as charantin, vicine, and polypeptide-p, as well as several antioxidants which could benefit a person with diabetes. The mechanism of action, whether it is via regulation of insulin release or altered glucose metabolism and its insulin-like effect, is still being evaluated. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/BitterOrange.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-11&quot; src=&quot;http://www.dietrxpill.info/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/BitterOrange.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bitter Melon Extracted Blood Sugar&quot; width=&quot;185&quot; height=&quot;298&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;CPprodDet&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial; font-size: medium;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Dietary Supplement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Bitter Melon has been used for centuries for its broad health benefits.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;diabetes-study&quot;&gt;Diabetes Study&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Antidiabetic activities of triterpenoids isolated from bitter melon associated with activation of the AMPK pathway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chem Biol. 2008. State Key Laboratory of Drug Research, Shanghai Institute of Materia Medica, Shanghai Institutes for Biological Sciences, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Shanghai, China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four cucurbitane glycosides, momordicosides Q, R, S, and T, and stereochemistry-established karaviloside XI, were isolated from the vegetable bitter melon (Momordica charantia). These compounds and their aglycones exhibited a number of biologic effects beneficial to diabetes and obesity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;biter-melon-benefits-in-animals&quot;&gt;Biter Melon Benefits in Animals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitter melon may be of benefit to lower plasma lipids and blood sugar in animal studies. Bitter melon may have benefit for diabetes in humans but human research is needed with bitter melon supplements to confirm or dispute these animal studies. As of 2010, most of the benefits with bitter melon extracts have been evaluated in cell culture and studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial;&quot;&gt;Bitter melon (Momordica charantia L.) inhibits adipocyte hypertrophy and down regulates lipogenic gene expression in adipose tissue of diet-induced obese rats.&lt;br /&gt; Br J Nutr. 2007. Department of Health and Nutrition, Chia Nan University of Pharmacy and Science, Tainan, Taiwan.&lt;br /&gt; Bitter melon has been shown to ameliorate diet-induced obesity and insulin resistance. To examine the effect of bitter melon supplementation on cell size and lipid metabolism in adipose tissues, three groups of rats were respectively fed a high-fat diet supplemented without (HF group) or with 5 % lyophilised bitter melon powder (HFB group), or with 0.01 % thiazolidinedione (TZD) (HFT group). A group of rats fed a low-fat diet was also included as a normal control. Hyperinsulinaemia and glucose intolerance were observed in the HF group but not in HFT and HFB groups. Although the number of large adipocytes of both the HFB and HFT groups was significantly lower than that of the HF group, the adipose tissue mass, TAG content and glycerol-3-phosphate dehydrogenase activity of the HFB group were significantly lower than those of the HFT group, implying that bitter melon might reduce lipogenesis in adipose tissue.  These results indicate bitter melon can reduce insulin resistance as effective as the thedrug TZD used for diabetes. Furthermore, bitter melon can suppress the visceral fat accumulation and inhibit adipocyte hypertrophy, which may be associated with markedly down regulated expressions of lipogenic genes in the adipose.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial;&quot;&gt;Lipid lowering effects of Bitter Melon in HIV-1-protease inhibitor-treated human hepatoma cells, HepG2.&lt;br /&gt; Br J Pharmacol. 20064. Nerurkar PV, Lee YK, Linden EH, Lim S, Pearson L, Nerurkar VR.&lt;br /&gt; Laboratory of Metabolic Disorders and Alternative Medicine, Department of Molecular Biosciences and Bioengineering, College of Tropical Agriculture and Human Resources, Room 415H, East-West Road, Honolulu, HI&lt;br /&gt; Hyperlipidemic effects of HIV-1-protease inhibitors (PI) are associated with increased hepatic production of triglyceride (TG)-rich lipoproteins, rather than lipoprotein clearance. PI are known to increase apolipoprotein B (apoB) secretion, apoC-III mRNA expression and decrease apoA-1 secretion. Nutritional therapy remains an important strategy to manage PI-associated hyperlipidemia. This study investigated the in vitro efficacy of Asian vegetable, bitter melon to ameliorate PI-associated apoB and lipid abnormalities in HepG2 cells. Our study demonstrates that bitter melon juice significantly reduced apoB secretion and apoC-III mRNA expression and normalized apoA-I expression in PI-treated HepG2 cells. Bitter melon juice also significantly reduced cellular triglyceride and microsomal TG transfer protein, suggesting that lipid bioavailability and lipidation of apoB assembly may play a role in decreased apoB secretion. Identifying molecular targets of bitter melon may offer alternative dietary strategies to decrease PI-associated hyperlipidemia and improve quality of life among HIV-1-infected patients.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial;&quot;&gt;Reduced adiposity in bitter melon (Momordica charantia)-fed rats is associated with increased lipid oxidative enzyme activities and uncoupling protein expression.&lt;br /&gt; J Nutr. 20053. Food and Nutritional Science Program, Department of Zoology, The University of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, The People’s Republic of China.&lt;br /&gt; To further explore the antiobesity effect of freeze-dried bitter melon juice, activities of mitochondrial lipid oxidative enzymes as well as the expression of uncoupling proteins and their transcription coactivator peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor-gamma coactivator-1 alpha (PGC-1alpha) were determined in diet-induced obese (DIO) rats. Rats were fed high-fat (HF) diets to induce obesity, and the effect of bitter melon was assessed at doses of 0.75, 1.0, or 1.25% (wt:wt). In a dose-response experiment, bitter melon -supplemented rats had lower energy efficiency (g weight gained/kJ consumed), visceral fat mass, serum glucose, and insulin resistance index, but higher plasma norepinephrine than unsupplemented rats. The present results suggest that decreased adiposity in bitter melon -supplemented rats may result from lower metabolic efficiency, a consequence of increased lipid oxidation and mitochondrial uncoupling.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bitter-melon-side-effects&quot;&gt;Bitter Melon Side Effects&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of 2010, no major bitter melon side effects have been reported in the medical literature.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>6,7-Dihydroxybergamottin</title>
   <link href="https://www.dietrxpill.info/67dihydroxybergamottin.html"/>
   <updated>2014-11-06T16:44:49-05:00</updated>
   <id>https://www.dietrxpill.info/67dihydroxybergamottin</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial;&quot;&gt;6,7-Dihydroxybergamottin is a furanocoumarin that inhibits CYP3A4 and is found in grapefruit juice and Seville orange juice. A number of furanocoumarins isolated from grapefruit juice have been found to inhibit CYP3A4 activity in vitro including 6′,7′-epoxybergamottin, 6′,7′-dihydroxybergamottin and bergamottin.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Arial;&quot;&gt;As of 2010, no human studies with 6,7-Dihydroxybergamottin supplements have been published on Medline.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
